Deepak Bisht

Master of Computer Applications with 6+ years of experience. I possess good knowledge of developing scalable software solutions using microservices based architecture. Strong collaboration, communication, presentation and interpersonal skills with proficiency in grasping new technical concepts and utilizing them in productive manner.

Work History

2019-07-Current

Senior Software Engineer

CVENT, Gurugram, Haryana

- Email-Sub System: Working as a Backend Developer to enhance the email system of CVENT to send all emails related to events.
- On-Site Solutions: Working as a full stack developer to enhance lead-capture services.

2018-11 -2019-07

Software Engineer

ION Trading, Noida, Uttar Pradesh

 Developed report generation tool for analysis of performance of assets on the basis of data gathered by all products at ION

2016-06 -2018-11

Software Engineer

Times Internet, Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Push-Notification: Individually developed Central Notification System for all Times Group websites and Mobile apps, integrated recommendation for sending user preferred alerts.

Times Food and Recipes: Worked as a backend developer and developed API's for entire recipe site, provided functionality for adding recipes, chef profile, conversion of units, shopping list and integration of shopping list with grocery vendors.

Cache Manager: Worked as an individual contributor to build entire backend for cleaning cache of all Times Group Websites, provided priority purging for showing latest updates on news sites in election campaigns and results.

Personal Info

Address

I-701,I-Tower,Ace Aspire Greater Noida West, Uttar Pradesh, 201318

Phone

+91 989 125 6736

E-mail

deepak.bisht@outlook.com bisht.1991@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/deepaksinghbisht/

Skills

Programming Languages:-Core Java, Python, TypeScript

Tools and Technologies: Spring, Spring-Boot, Dropwizard, RabbitMQ , GIT, BitBucket, Numpy, Pandas, AWS, S3, Sagemaker, Cloudformation, A21, Karate

Operating Systems : Linux, Macintosh and Windows

Databases: CouchBase, MS SQL Server, MongoDB, and MySQL and PostGreSQL

2014-09 - Software Engineer 2015-12

U2opa Mobile, Gurugram, Haryana

 Fonetwish Enterprise, Discussion Forum and Marketplace -Worked as a Junior Developer and created API's which helps in creation of USSD Applications, allows access to social network websites like Facebook, Twitter via Feature phones. Different organizations can post their USSD application requirement on Market Place and assign them to developers.

Education

2014 Masters: Computer Science

Jamia Millia Islamia, New Delhi

Graduated with 8.0 GPA

2011 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

University of Delhi, New DelhiGraduated with 7.0 GPA

2008 Intermediate: Science and Mathematics

Sunrise Ville School, Uttar Pradesh

GPA: 8.2

2006 High School Diploma

Sunrise Ville School, Noida

GPA: 7.5

Awards and Certifications

Machine Learning Engineer, Udacity

M101J, M201 from MongoDB University

1st prize in the event Co-Dennis(C/C++) at Envisage '13 annual technical fest organized by University of Delhi

1st position in the event Java-Pro at Algorhythm '13